

ROHINI TOMAR

WEB DEVELOPER



WHO I AM AT A GLANCE

A Full Stack Web Developer with an experience in developing various projects from scratch (frontend and backend). Background in teaching have helped me mastered my Reflective Thinking which includes observation, communication, team working, critical thinking ,judgment and decision making. I am looking forward to leverage my technical knowledge and experience to consolidate and improve my skills as a Developer and be a leader to achieve organization's goals and career objectives.

KEEP IN TOUCH:

Cell: 925-997-7062 rohini.tomar@gmail.com 2863 Enfield Street, San Ramon , CA- 94582

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

- Front-End Dev: HTML, CSS, Web Accessibility, css grid and Flexbox
- Responsive Web Design
- Git and Version Control
- Cross Browser Testing and Debugging
- Web Hosting
- JavaScript, Ajax, jQuery Bootstrap SQL
- PostgreSQL, API Configuration
- JavaScript Frameworks : React, Angular, Vue.js
- Test Driven Development : Unit Testing, Integration Testing
- Progressive Web Application

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

- **pokedex**-- I created a jquery website that pulls data from pokeapi.co .
- Myflix -- This is my first full stack application made with React. The backend is built with Node and the data is stored on MongoDB. User accounts are authenticated and authorized using passport and JSON
- QuizApp--This is an Angular project created using HTML & CSS, JavaScript and Angular.JS
- **Meetup app**-- Meetup App is a Web Progressive App that uses the meetup API and AWS.
- **Chatapp**-- Its a native mobile app created using reactnative.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

New horizon college, Bangalore

Lecturer In Physics - 2010-2016

University College, K.U.K

Lecturer In Physics - 2005-2006

Having worked with Youth made me learn to stay up to date with the industry and build a strong team together. I want to further apply my love for coding and newly accuired skills in Web Development and drive the process of designing websites.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

CAREERFOUNDRY

Full Stack Web Development Course

- Certificate In Intro To Front End Development Jul 2019 Aug 2020
- Certificate In Full Stack Immersion Course Aug 2020 Apr 2020

DEPT. OF PHYSICS, K.U.K

Master Of Physics - 2003-2005

UNIVERSITY COLLEGE, K.U.K

BACHELORS OF COMPUTER SCIENCE - 2000-2003

CMC, A GOVERNMENT OF INDIA ENTERPRISE

Diploma In Software Technology - 2002-2003